bigideasmath.com 2019-11-13

# Big Ideas Math | Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy (“Policy”), effective 07/01/2016, tells you about Big Ideas Learning, LLC’s privacy practices governing personal information we may collect when you visit our bigideasmath.com website, and how we may use and share that information. Your prior activities on the site may have been governed by an earlier version of this Policy.

From time to time, we may use your information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our Policy. If our information practices do change materially, we will post the changes to our website and revise our Policy accordingly. In addition, if we have collected personally-identifying information from you, we will notify you and secure your consent before using your personal information in new ways.

### What Information Do We Collect?

### Personal Information:

We collect personal and contact information you choose to provide to us in connection with your activities on the site. What we collect depends on whether you register through Clever or on our site directly. In either case, if you are a minor, your school has acted as your parent or guardian’s agent and has consented to this collection on your behalf. If you are under 13 years old, this consent fulfills our obligation under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act. Our collection of personal information to set up your account is in furtherance of our performance of services otherwise performed by school employees, is under the direct control of the school with respect to the use and maintenance of educational records, and complies with use and redisclosure requirements regarding personal information from education records, all in compliance with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.

#### Registration through Clever:

Schools may register their students for bigideasmath.com through Clever, a third-party service providing single login functionality for a variety of educational applications. Schools will provide Clever with the following information for each teacher and student: 

  * First and last name
  * School name and school address
  * Individual’s school email address

Schools may opt to share additional student information with Clever, such as gender or date of birth. Your personal information is stored and encrypted by Clever, not by us, but we are able to view this information. Information you provide to Clever directly is governed by its privacy policy, which you can find here: <https://clever.com/about/privacy-policy>. 

#### Registration by Teacher:

A teacher may choose to register directly through our site. The district will provide each teacher with a link and a district or school- level access code so the teacher can set up an account. The teacher will provide us with the following information: 

  * Teacher’s first and last name
  * School name and school address
  * Teacher’s school email address.

The teacher will provide each student in the registered class with a link and access code so the student can set up an account. The student will provide us with the following information: 

  * First and last name
  * Student ID

The teacher and student will also set up passwords. 

### Other user information we collect:

In addition, for each visitor to our site, we automatically gather certain other potentially identifying information and store it in log files. This information includes (as applicable) date/time stamp, student answers to questions, scores, access to assignments, live chat transcripts, and time spent on assessments. We collect and store this information on an individual basis and in aggregate, or combined, form. We use proprietary algorithms to calculate behavior, knowledge, and skill statistics using individual simulation activity for each student. 

#### “Do Not Track” Signals.

We do not currently have the capability to recognize browser “Do Not Track” signals. We adhere to the standards set forth in this privacy policy.

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site will be limited. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. We use session cookies to record session information, such as which web pages a user has visited, and to track user activity on the site. We also use session cookies to store any passwords used on the site (such as a password associated with a user account), so you don’t have to enter it more than once per session. These cookies are deleted when you close your web browser.

#### Analytics

To determine how many users visit our site, how often they visit this site, and to better understand the areas of greatest interest to our visitors, we use a tools called “Google Analytics” to compile this information for us. As a result of your visit to our site, Google may collect information such as your domain type, your IP address and clickstream information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of analytics tools with personally identifiable information. For more information about the analytics companies’ ability to use and share information about your visits to this site, see <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.

### How Do We Use and Share the Information We Collect?

We store and process your Personal Information to authenticate your user’s license and to grant you access to the applicable materials.

We also use information we collect to analyze trends, to administer the site, and to track users’ movements around the site. We also use this information to improve the site and to make it more useful to visitors.

We do not share Personal Information we collect on this site with any third parties, except that (i) we may share student assessment results (grades and the like) with Clever if the school has registered through that third party service, and (ii) we may share Personal Information where we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process.

It is possible that, at some time in the future, our company may be sold along with its assets, or may engage in business transactions in which customer information is one of the assets transferred. In such a case, the customer information which we have gathered may be one of the business assets we transfer.

### How Long Do We Keep the Information We Collect?

We will retain your Personal Information in accordance with our continuing business need to service this relationship and/or to improve our site.

### How to Correct Information

A teacher who has registered on our site may update or correct his or her own Personal Information and the Personal Information of his or her students that we maintain. Teachers registered through Clever may update information according to the procedures Clever has in place.

### Security

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, and to guard that information against loss, misuse, or alteration.

Please note, however, that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we use commercially-reasonable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Links to Third Party Sites

This Policy applies only to information collected by this website. From time to time, this website may link you to other sites (“Linked Sites”) that are not owned by us. We do not control the collection or use of any information, including Personal Information, that occurs during your visit to the Linked Sites. Further, we make no representations about the privacy policies or practices of the Linked Sites, and we are not responsible for their privacy practices.

Be careful of disclosing any of your personally identifiable information when leaving our site. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of every website that collects personally identifiable information.

### Questions About Our Privacy Policy and Practices

If you have any questions about the Policy or our privacy practices, you may contact:

Big Ideas Learning, LLC  
1762 Norcross Road  
Erie, PA 16510  
(877) 552 – 7766  
legal@bigideaslearning.com
